Guide to the Sara and Gerald Murphy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize and Rolled Storage, 5.88 linear feet (30 boxes)
  - Oversize
    - Unsigned children's drawings and empty portfolio case (Series II), undated (Box 147, Folder 1418-1419)
    - Diploma for Gerald Murphy from Saint Joseph's Abbey (Series II), 1964 October 20 (Box 147, Folder 1420)
    - Advertisements from The Literary Digest and Ladies Home Journal (Series II), 1918 and 1927 (Box 147, Folder 1421)
    - Empty quatrefoil folder (Series II), undated (Box 147, Folder 1422)
    - Survey of Villa America property by G. Vailland (Series II), 1932 June (Box 148, Folder 1423)
    - Blueprints and plans for renovations to "Cheer Hall," Sneden's Landing, by Hale Walker (Series II), circa 1949 (Box 148, Folder 1424)
    - Donnelly, Honoria Murphy by Studio Harcourt, Paris (Series III), circa 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1425)
    - Donnelly, Honoria Murphy by Blackstone Studios, Shelburne, New York (Series III), circa 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1426)
    - Donnelly, Honoria Murphy by Blackstone Studios, New York (Series III), circa 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1427)
    - Murphy, Frederic by Histed, New York (Series III), 1914 (Box 149, Folder 1428)
    - Murphy, Gerald by Pierce, New York (Series III), circa 1900 (Box 149, Folder 1429)
    - Murphy, Gerald, New York (Series III), circa 1908 (Box 149, Folder 1430)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg (Series III), circa 1900 (Box 149, Folder 1431)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg, debutante portrait (Series III), circa 1905 (Box 149, Folder 1432)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg by Keturah Collings, London (Series III), 1907 (Box 149, Folder 1433)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg by Conway Studios, New York (Series III), circa 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1434)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg by Associated Photographic Service and Blackstone Studios, New York (Series III), circa 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1435-1436)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg sitting on plaid couch holding dogs by Carlyle Studios, New York (Series III), 1947 (Box 149, Folder 1437)
    - Murphy, Sara Wiborg holding roses possibly by Edward Rice (Series III), 1965 (Box 149, Folder 1438)
    - Wiborg, Adeline Sherman by Davis and Sanford, New York (Series III), undated (Box 150, Folder 1439)
    - Wiborg, Adeline Sherman in elaborate dress (Series III) [14 x 18], undated (Box 150, Folder 1440)
    - Wiborg, Frank Bestow by Bellsmith, Cincinnati, Ohio (Series III), circa 1898 (Box 150, Folder 1441)
    - Wiborg, Frank Bestow by Benjamin Portraits, Cincinnati, Ohio and engraving based on photograph by E.G. Williams and Brothers, New York (Series III), undated (Box 150, Folder 1442)
    - Wiborg, Frank Bestow reproduction by Hollinger and Company (Series III), undated (Box 150, Folder 1443)
    - Wiborg, Mary Hoyt by Kazanjian, New York (Series III), circa 1908 (Box 150, Folder 1444)
    - Wiborg, Mary Hoyt on horseback by Paul Thompson, New York and unidentified (Series III), circa 1910 (Box 150, Folder 1445)
    - Wiborg, Mary Hoyt by unidentified studio, 3, Place de la Madeleine, Paris, France (Series III), circa 1920 (Box 150, Folder 1446)
    - Gerald Murphy holding Patrick by Marshall, Cambridge, Massachusetts (Series III), circa 1920 (Box 151, Folder 1447)
    - Murphy children by A. Sovignity, Photographie Victor-Hugo, Paris (Series III), circa 1921 (Box 151, Folder 1448)
    - Wiborg family at Fourth of July party in a park (Series III), 1889 July 4 (Box 151, Folder 1449)
    - Wiborg family by E.B. Core, Cincinnati, Ohio (Series III), circa 1891 and 1984 (Box 151, Folder 1450)
    - Wiborg girls seated in front of tapestry possibly at the Dunes by Pierce, New York (Series III), circa 1909 (Box 151, Folder 1451)
    - Allen, Henry T. (Series III), undated (Box 152, Folder 1452)
    - Benchley, Robert with dog, on stage, and smoking with Marc Connelly (Series III), undated (Box 152, Folder 1453)
    - MacLeish, Archibald with basket of peaches, portrait by The Sunday Bulletin, Philadelphia, and portrait by unidentified photographer (Series III), undated (Box 152, Folder 1454)
    - Sherman, John by Rockwood (Series III), 1885 (Box 152, Folder 1455)
    - Sherman, William Tecumseh photograph and engravings by J.C. Curdy and Co., Philadelphia and William Sartain, Philadelphia (Series III), 1888 and 1883 (Box 152, Folder 1456)
    - Unidentified (Series III), circa 1850-1940 (Box 152, Folder 1457-1461)
    - Wiborg mansion: Exterior view with people playing croquet on lawn (Series III), circa (Box 152, Folder 1462)
    - The Dunes: Photographs of the exterior and interior (Series III), After 1896 (Box 152, Folder 1463)
    - Album containing photographs and clippings documenting Prince Hohenzollerns's visit to the U.S.A. (Series III), 1904 (Box 152, Folder 1464)
    - Fish, Olga Wiborg sitting in front of Picasso painting (Series III), Before 1937 (Box 153, Folder 1465)
    - Wiborg sisters by Pierce, New York (Series III), 1908 (Box 153, Folder 1466)
    - Wiborg family riding elephants, Jaipur, India (Series III), 1914 (Box 153, Folder 1467)
    - Olga's wedding with Sara and Mary Hoyt as bridesmaids by Mr. and Mrs. Bradey, New York (Series III), 1915 (Box 153, Folder 1468)
    - Sherman, William Tecumseh photograph and engravings by J.C. Curdy and Co., Philadelphia and William Sartain, Philadelphia (Series III), 1888 and 1883 (Box 153, Folder 1469)
    - Wiborg, Susan with Frank and Harry Wiborg (Series III), undated (Box 153, Folder 1470)
    - Drawings "3 positions for Auratum" and of table with a plant (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1471)
    - Photograph of detail from "Bibliothèque" (Series IV), After 1927 (Box 154, Folder 1472)
    - Photographs of painting "Wasp and Pear" (Series IV), after 1929 (Box 154, Folder 1473)
    - "Harvard L.A. [landscaping architecture] school work signed by Sara Murphy [rolled; needs preservation attention] (Series IV), 1919 November (Box 154, Folder 1474)
    - Watercolor of Baoth in crib (Series IV), 1919 (Box 154, Folder 1475)
    - Portrait of Gerald Murphy (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1476)
    - Woman sitting in a garden (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1477)
    - Ornate table with candles, flowers, and a mirror painted in Paris (Series IV), May 10 (Box 154, Folder 1478)
    - Drawings of nudes and of two women on a couch with a man standing behind them (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1479)
    - Drawing of boy wearing a skull cap (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1480)
    - Drawing of a single rose in a vase (Series IV), undated (Box 154, Folder 1481)
    - Conant, Kenneth, two drawings "Palma de Mallorca -- The Seu [cathedral] from the Paseo (on the ramparts)" and "Cathedral from near the Puerta de Talaverz, Plasencia [Spain]" (Series IV), 1920 (Box 154, Folder 1482-1483)
    - Brown leather briefcase and felt Mark Cross merchandise bag (Series V), undated (Box 155, Folder 1484)
    - Black alligator briefcase with red leather lining and felt Mark Cross merchandise bag (Series V), undated (Box 155, Folder 1485)
    - Black leather portfolio with red leather lining and felt Mark Cross merchandise bag (Series V), undated (Box 156, Folder 1486)
    - Black leather envelope case with strap, buckle, and luggage tag (Series V) [11 X 17], undated (Box 156, Folder 1487)
    - Stiff red leather folder (Series V), undated (Box 156, Folder 1488)
    - Green leather Traveler's map case stamped "Honoria Murphy, care Guaranty Trust Company" (Series V), undated (Box 156, Folder 1489)
    - Garment bags (Series V), undated (Box 157, Folder 1490-1491)
    - Silver tray with "Wiborg" engraved on face (Series V), undated (Box 158, Folder 1492)
    - Silver commemorative plaque mounted on wood engraved "To, Gerald Murphy, President, In Appreciation for his Constant Inspiration and Understanding, from, The Mark Cross Employees, of the Centenary Year 1945" and felt Mark Cross merchandise bag (Series V) (Box 159, Folder 1493)
    - Plaque with Mark Cross England trademark logo and Mark Cross merchandise bag (Series V), circa 1940 (Box 159, Folder 1494)
    - Table runner and circular place mats used by Murphys while living in Antibes (Series V) [16 X 20], circa 1920 (Box 160, Folder 1495-1497)
    - Flag from Weatherbird (Series V), undated (Box 160, Folder 1498)
    - Blue leather photograph album with gold tooling "John Charles Baoth Donnelly, June 20th, 1951" (Series V) (Box 161, Folder 1499)
    - Blue leather scrapbook with gold tooling "J.C.B.D." (Series V), circa 1951 (Box 161, Folder 1500)
    - Beige leather photograph album with gold tooling (Series V), undated (Box 162, Folder 1501)
    - Beige leather scrapbook with gold tooling (Series V), undated (Box 162, Folder 1502)
    - Scrapbook with "collections of movie cut-out pictures of my favorites -- fashions of my time when I was around fourteen years old" (Series VII), 1932 (Box 163, Folder 1503-1504)
    - Cover art for Sara & Gerald (Series VII), before 1982 (Box 164, Folder 1505)
    - City Lights Books. "Great Literary Encounters" calendar with photograph of Ernest Hemingway, Fraulein Glaser, John Dos Passos, and Gerald Murphy skiing on the cover (Series VII), 1981 (Box 164, Folder 1506)
    - Ghilaga, Tess. "Lost Horizons." Hamptons (Series VII), 2000 May 26-June 1 (Box 164, Folder 1507)
    - Markus, Julia. "Palmy Days Along the Riviera." The New York Times Magazine (Series VII), 1994 March 6 (Box 164, Folder 1508)
    - Reproductions of Gerald Murphy's artwork in various publications (Series VII), 1993-2004 (Box 164, Folder 1509)
    - Reviews of Sara & Gerald (Series VII), 1982-1983 (Box 165, Folder 1510-1512)
    - The Phillips Collection, "Americans in Paris" (Series VII), 1996 (Box 165, Folder 1513)
    - F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald (Series VII), 1955-1996 (Box 165, Folder 1514)
    - Ernest Hemingway (Series VII), 1951-1981 (Box 165, Folder 1515)
    - Various clippings and notes regarding marketing for the Mark Cross Company (Series VIII), 1913-1928, undated (Box 166, Folder 1516-1518)
    - Print of Ault & Wiborg Co. poster by Toulouse-Lautrec (Series IX), undated (Box 167, Folder 1519)
    - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings collected by Frank Wiborg (Series IX), 1927-1930 (Box 167, Folder 1520)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1875 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1521)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1882 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1522)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1892 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1523)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1893 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1524)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1894 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1525)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1895 (Series IX) (Box 168, Folder 1526)
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1914 (Series IX), 1913-1914 (Box 168, Folder 1527)
    - Black leather attaché case with beige interior (Series V), undated (Box 172)
    - Clipping from The Massachusetts Spy (Series X), 1863 January 28 (Folder 1528 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1891 (Series IX) (Folder 1529 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1896 (Series IX) (Folder 1530 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1897 (Series IX) (Folder 1531 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1898 (Series IX) (Folder 1532 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1899 (Series IX) (Folder 1533 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1901 (Series IX) (Folder 1534 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1903 (Series IX) (Folder 1535 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1904 (Series IX) (Folder 1536 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1905 (Series IX) (Folder 1537 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1906 (Series IX) (Folder 1538 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1907 (Series IX) (Folder 1539 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1908 (Series IX) (Folder 1540 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1909 (Series IX) (Folder 1541 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1910 (Series IX) (Folder 1542 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1911 (Series IX), 1911-1912 (Folder 1543 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1912 (Series IX) (Folder 1544 (Broadside))
    - Frank Wiborg Diary: 1913 (Series IX) (Folder 1545 (Broadside))
    - Gerald Murphy and the Fifth Company during WWI (Series IX), circa 1917 (Folder 1546 (Broadside))
    - Baoth Murphy with classmates, by Thompson, Yonkers, New York (Series IX), 1930s (Folder 1547 (Broadside oversize))
  - Rolled Storage
    - Various pieces of cloth (Series V), undated (Box 1549 (Roll))
    - Tablecloths (Series V), undated (Box 1550 (Roll))
- Restricted Fragile Material
  Boxes 170-171 and 199-204a contain fragile documents and nitrate negatives and may be seen only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation surrogates have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
  Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted pending reformatting. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for information about reference copies.
  - Restricted Fragile: Clippings
    - Box 146, folders 1402-1415 (Box 170, Folder 1551-1553)
    - Boxes 119-120, folders 1242-1249 (Box 171, Folder 1554-1556)
  - Restricted Fragile: Photograph Negatives
    - Box 21, folder 333 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1557)
    - Box 24, folders 426-428 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1558)
    - Box 27, folder 524 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1559)
    - Box 27, folder 524 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1560)
    - Box 27, folder 527 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1561)
    - Box 27, folder 528 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1562)
    - Box 27, folders 529-530 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1562a)
    - Box 27, folder 531 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1563)
    - Box 27, folder 531 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1564)
    - Box 27, folders 533-535 (Box 199 (Cold storage), Folder 1565)
    - Box 27, folders 533-535 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1566-1568)
    - Box 28, folder 540 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1569)
    - Box 28, folder 540 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1570)
    - Box 28, folders 544-548 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1571)
    - Box 28, folder 550 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1572)
    - Box 28, folder 550 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1573)
    - Box 28, folder 553 (Box 200 (Cold storage), Folder 1574)
    - Box 28, folder 558 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1575)
    - Box 29, folder 566 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1576)
    - Box 29, folder 566 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1577)
    - Box 29, folders 567-568 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1578)
    - Box 29, folders 567-568 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1579)
    - Box 29, folder 572 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1580)
    - Box 29, folders 573-578 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1581-1583)
    - Box 29, folders 573-578 (Box 201 (Cold storage), Folder 1584-1585)
    - Box 29, folder 579 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1586)
    - Box 29, folder 579 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1587)
    - Box 30, folder 581 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1588)
    - Box 30, folder 582 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1589)
    - Box 30, folder 582 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1590)
    - Box 30, folder 583 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1591)
    - Box 30, folder 584 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1592)
    - Box 30, folder 584 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1593)
    - Box 30, folder 586 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1594)
    - Box 30, folders 588-589 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1595-1596)
    - Box 30, folders 588-589 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1597-1599)
    - Box 30, folder 593 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1600)
    - Box 30, folder 593 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1601)
    - Box 30, folder 594 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1602)
    - Box 30, folder 594 (Box 202 (Cold storage), Folder 1603)
    - Box 30, folder 596 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1604)
    - Box 30, folder 596 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1605)
    - Box 30, folder 597 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1606)
    - Box 30, folder 598 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1607)
    - Box 31, folders 603-607 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1608-1610)
    - Box 31, folders 603-607 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1611)
    - Box 32, folder 629 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1612)
    - Box 32, folder 629 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1613)
    - Box 32, folder 633 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1614)
    - Box 32, folder 633 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1615)
    - Box 31, folders 612-613 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1616)
    - Box 31, folders 612-613 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1617)
    - Box 32, folder 623 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1618)
    - Box 32, folder 623 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1619)
    - Box 33, folder 644 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1620)
    - Box 33, folder 645 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1621)
    - Box 33, folder 645 (Box 203 (Cold storage), Folder 1622-1623)
    - Box 33, folder 646 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1624)
    - Box 33, folder 647 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1625)
    - Boxes 32-33, folders 641-642 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1626)
    - Box 33, folder 648 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1627)
    - Box 33, folder 656 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1628)
    - Box 33, folder 658 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1629)
    - Box 33, folder 660 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1630)
    - Box 35, folder 647 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1630a)
    - Box 37, folder 720 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1631)
    - Box 37, folder 720 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1632)
    - Box 38, folder 724 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1633)
    - Box 40, folder 757 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1634)
    - Boxes 40-42, folders 760-777 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1635-1636)
    - Boxes 40-42, folders 760-777 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1637)
    - Box 42, folder 781 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1638)
    - Box 43, folder 785 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1639)
    - Box 47, folders 793-794 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1640)
    - Box 52, folder 802 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1641)
    - Boxes 54-55, folders 813-819 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1642-1643)
    - Boxes 56-57, folders 820-842 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1644)
    - Boxes 58-59, folders 843-870 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1645-1647)
    - Box, 62, folders 886-887 (Box 204a (Cold storage), Folder 1648)
    - Box 128, folders 1314-1318 (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1649)
    - Damaged negatives (Box 204 (Cold storage), Folder 1650)